Guide to the Joseph Desloge river running video collection 1942-1958
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
Joseph Desloge river running video collection
1942-1958
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 (801) 581-8864
A0641
Desloge, Joseph, 1889-1971
23 16mm films, 2 8mm films and 7 VHS videocassettes
The Joseph Desloge river running video collection (1942-1958) consists almost entirely of footage of river trips on the Green and Colorado Rivers. Several films were shot at the Grand Canyon. The collection also contains movies of trips on other rivers and of the Desloge family's other vacations and home life. Joseph Desloge was a St. Louis industrialist and philanthropist who frequently vacationed on the rivers of the West and joined expeditions led by prominent river guides of the mid 20th century.
Biographical Note
Joseph "Joe" Desloge (1889-1971) was born in St. Louis, Missouri to Lydia Davis and Firmin Vincent Desloge, who had moved to St. Louis to attend St. Louis University. A descendant of French immigrants, Joseph Desloge served in the French army in WWI and was decorated for bravery near Vouziers. He graduated from the Massachusettes Institute of Technology (MIT) in 1912 with a degree in electrical engineering and founded the Minerva Oil Company (miners of zinc and fluorspar), Killark Electric Manufacturing Company, Louisiana Manufacturing Company and Atlas Manufacturing Company. In 1946, built an elegant mansion in Florissant, Missouri, whcih he named "Vouziers" after the site of his glory in France. A frequent vacationer on the Colorado River, Desloge used his wealth to preserve and share natural landscapes in his home state by donating the land to create Johnson's Shut-Ins State Park in Reynold County, Missouri and Sunset Park in the city of Florissant. Desloge and his first wife, Anne Kennett Farrar, had four children. She died in 1934, and Desloge spent his later years with Anna Margaret Saalfrank, whom he married in 1953. Joseph Desloge passed away in 1971.
The Joseph Desloge river running video collection (1942-1958) consists almost entirely of original and composite print films and videocassettes of river trips on the Green and Colorado Rivers. Several films were shot at the Grand Canyon. The collection also contains movies of trips on other rivers and of the Desloge family's other vacations and home life.
The materials are arranged chronologically by format type.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
For photographs of some of these river trips see Northern Arizona University's Bill Belknap collection.
Marston, Otis R.; Colorado River (Colo.-Mexico); Green River (Wyo.-Utah); Grand Canyon (Ariz.); Rivers--West (U.S.); Rivers--Recreational use; Sports and Recreation; Moving Images; Moving images
- 16mm and 8mm films
  - Grand Canyon, 1942; 16mm film (Reel 1)
    With Otis "Dock" Marston.
  - Grand Canyon - Colorado River parts 1-2, 1942-1948; 16mm film (Reel 2-3)
  - Grand Canyon, 1950; 16mm film (Reel 4)
    This copy does not contain parts excerpted for composite print on 09/20/1954.
  - Grand Canyon riverways, 1951; 16mm film (Reel 5)
  - Grand Canyon - Colorado River parts 1-2, 1951; 16mm film (Reel 6-7)
    With Otis "Dock" Marston and others.
  - Four vacations, 1951-1955; 16mm film (Reel 8)
    Mexico City, Guadalajara (1951)
    Green River, Hell's Half Mile (1953)
    Wind River Mountains river trip with Erma and Christy (1954)
    Green River (1955)
  - Motor boating in Grand Canyon, 1952; 16mm film (Reel 9)
  - Green River and oil fields, 1952; 16mm film (Reel 10)
    Joe Desloge, A.H., M.D. and Zoe Desloge.
  - Green River, 1952; 16mm film (Reel 11)
    Joe Desloge, Marie Saalfrank and A.K. Reynolds.
  - Colorado River, 1955; 8mm film (Reel 12)
    With Hugh Cutler, Otis "Dock" Marston and others.
  - Grand Canyon, 1956; 16mm film (Reel 13)
  - Grand Canyon, 1958; 16mm film (Reel 14)
    Composite print including boat upset, Otis "Dock" Marston, etc.
  - Unidentified film, undated; 16mm film (Reel 15)
  - Colorado River, Green River, San Juan River, undated; 16mm film (Reel 16)
  - Unidentified film, undated; 16mm film (Reel 17)
  - Green River, Colorado River, San Juan River, undated; 16mm film (Reel 18)
    Four separate river trips are included on this film reel. Participants include Norman Nevills, Otis "Dock Marston," H.K., Loc Moore, Arthur, (M)Hilotte, Comptons.
  - Hudson River, undated; 8mm film (Reel 19)
    Boat trip, Statue of Liberty, New York City skyline, etc.
  - San Juan, undated; 16mm film (Reel 20)
  - Green River, undated; 16mm film (Reel 21)
    With Norman Nevills, Anne Desloge, B.D., Zoe Desloge, Marie Saalfrank, Comptons, Arthur, Botty and John.
  - Riverways of Rapidsmen parts 1-2, undated; 16mm film (Reel 22-23)
  - Colorado River reel 2, undated; 16mm film (Reel 24)
    Helicopter, etc.
  - Unidentified film, undated; 16mm film (Reel 25)
- VHS videocassettes
  These videos are arranged in the order in which they appear on the videocassettes, with 1.1 being the first film on the first cassette, 1.2 being the second film on the first cassette and so on.
  These cassettes contain footage of river trips and occasional other home movies dubbed from 16mm or 8mm film. Scenes were filmed in the Grand Canyon unless otherwise noted.
  - Otis Marston presents: Through the Grand Canyon by boat., circa 1942; VHS videocassette Color, sound (Cassette 1.1)
    Otis Marston narrates:
    Maps of river and Grand Canyon
    Rapids, water, scenery
    "Ross Wheeler" (boat)
    Scenery, aerials of Hoover Dam
    Norman Nevills in boat
    Norman Nevills on shore
    Norman Nevills demonstrating "face your danger" river running technique with model, diagram
    Scenes of boats
    Loading boats at Lees Ferry
    Launch, with powerboat in background (unidentified boat)
    Running rapids (not Badger Creek Rapid)
    Hiking near Tanner Flats
    Granaries at Nankoweap Canyon
    Rapids
    Norman Nevills giving signals while someone else runs rapid
    Desert View Watchtower on south rim of Grand Canyon
    Norman Nevills building signal fire
    Camp, breakfast
    Phanton Ranch, swimming in pool, loading boats at Bright Angel Creek
    Lining Horn Creek Rapid
    Running rapids in Middle Granite Gorge
    Diamond Peak
    End of trip, tow-out on Lake Mead
    Hoover Dam
  - San Francisco, Green River to Colorado River travelogue, undated; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 1.2)
    San Francisco Bay, San Francisco street scenes including streetcars on turntables, streets
    Woman at typewriter
    Russell Henderson typing in Grand Canyon
    Randall Henderson leaving note in can in cairn
    Map of Green and Colorado Rivers
    Aerials of mountains
    Rapids in Gore Canyon, Colorado River
    moving water
    Flaming Gorge, Green River
    Uinta Mountains
    Upper Green River: Ashley Falls, Browns Park, Gates of Lodore, Hell's Half Mile, rapid, Echo Park, Highway 40 bridge at Jensen, Utah
    Aerial of confluence of Green and Colorado
    Rapids in Cataract Canyon (?)
    Glen Canyon
    Hole-in-the-Rock
    Otis Marston
    Mouth of San Juan River
    Lees Ferry
    Aerial of Vermillion Cliffs, Marble Canyon
    Map of Grand Canyon region
    View from rim of Grand Canyon
    Marble Canyon
    Stanton's Cave
    Vasey's Paradise
    View from south rim
    Bridge at Cameron, Arizona, over Little Colorado River
    Angel's Window, north rim of Grand Canyon
    View from north rim into Unkar Delta area
    Tanner Flats
    Carbon Creek - Tanner Rapid
    View into upper Granite Gorge, Bright Angel area
    Phantom Ranch swimming pool
    Inner Gorge
    Scouting rapids
    Lining Lava Falls - Norman Nevills, Garth Marston, others; Margaret Marston filming
    Reloading below Lava falls, re-launching boats
    Lining process in fast motion
    Portaging boats in Canyon of Lodore (out of sequence)
    Aerials of Grand Canyon
    Debris from 1944 crash of US Army transport airplane on north rim of Grand Canyon
    Power boats doing upruns
    Lake Mead
    Hoover Dam tour, riding aerial tramway
    Power lines
    The transition between videos 1.2 and 1.3 is unclear. They may not actually be separate films.
  - Green River to Colorado River and Southern Utah region travelogue, undated; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 1.3)
    Map of Green - Colorado River region
    Nankoweap ruins
    Marston twin girls with pottery
    John Wesley Powell with boats
    Powell party inscriptions at Music Temple, Glen Canyon
    plaque at Separation Rapid
    Stanton Expedition (?) photos
    Galloway inscription, Elves Chasm
    Emery Kolb with NPS park ranger
    Clyde Eddy
    Unidentified man
    Unidentified woman
    Lois Jotter
    Bert Loper
    Loper's boat
    uUnidentified man
    Hyde inscription
    Skeleton at South Cave
    Hiking in Glen Canyon with Norman Nevills
    Old mining site in Glen Canyon
    Wreck of Stanton (Hokasninni Mining Co.) dredge, after being set on fire
    Norman Nevills clowns with old clothes from trunk found in Glen Canyon
    Oil rig near Mexican Hat
    Cable car over San Juan River
    Bridges: Moab, Utah, Navajo Bridge over Marble Canyon (aerial, including flying under bridge; from land, and from river, Kaibab Bridge, near Phantom Ranch
    Bright Angel trail with mules
    Cable car at Bass Camp
    Natural bridges and arches: Wilson Arch, Angel's Window, Jug Handle Arch, Gregory Bridge, Delicate Arch, Druid Arch, Double-O Arch, Landscape Arch, Steven's Arch, Rainbow Bridge
    Map of southeast Utah
    Sorting canned good for river trip with Frank Wright
    Cooking, serving meal on river
    Washing dishes - Garth Marston
    Fossils
    Hiking, rock-hounding in badlands along river
    Southern Utah scenery
    Wildlife: lizard, scorpion, rattlesnake, deer swimming river, bighorn sheep, antelope, bison
    Sliding on smooth slope on air mattress
    Boats
    Rapids in Idaho, 1946 (out of sequence)
    Pres Walker being washed out of boat in rapid in Idaho, 1946 (out of sequence)
    Rapids, Grand Canyon: scouting, running bailing boats
    Starting driftwood fires
    Patticake
    The transition between videos 1.3 and 1.4 is unclear. They may not actually be separate films.
  - Grand Canyon river trip with Ed Hudson, circa 1940s; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 1.4)
    Ed Hudson
    Running Bedrock Rapid
    Hiking
    Water fights
    Havasu
    Windstorm with blowing sandbars
    Clouds in Glen Canyon
    Wind blowing spray off tops of waves
    Glen Canyon rainstorm
    Waterfalls off rim of canyon
    Rainbow
    Mexican Hat
    Shiprock
    Marston twin girls in front of Navajo Twins (rock formation), near Bluff, Utah
    Monument Valley scenes
    Grand Canyon scenery
    Swimming in river
    Sliding in mud
    Havasu: swimming, diving, boarding boats in mouth of Havasu Creek
    Little Colorado River: swimming, diving
    Lava flows
    Vulcan's Anvil
    Playing in mud
    Lava Falls
    Oarlocks on boats
    Rockfall
    Scouting rapids: NDN, Otis Marston, Garth Marston
    Swimming rapids in inner tubes, air mattresses, life jackets, without life jacket
    Dubendorff rapid
    Rapids from boats
    Otis Marston rowing boat
    Rapids from boat
    Travertine Falls
    Swirlies
    Lower Grand Canyon
    Garth Marston rowing
    Floatplane landing
    "Hae Dae" (power launch) on Lake Mead
    Towing out Nevills boats on Lake Mead
  - Grand Canyon river trip with Ed Hudson, 1950; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 2.1)
    Ed Hudson and other crew
    Bureau of Reclamation camp, Marble Canyon: aerial tramway, boats from rim
    Scenery: travertine waterfall
    Hiking to old mine, Tanner Flats
    South river of Grand Canyon views, near Unkar Delta, various rim scenery
    Camp: washing dishes
    Scenes around Hance Rapid
    Helicopter circling over boats and river
    Scenes from helicopter of boats in rapids
    Esmerelda II (boat)
    Helicopter
    Boats in rapids
    Abandonment of Esmerelda II
    Helicopter rescue of passengers: landing, Margaret Marston boarding
    Take-off of helicopter
    "SOS" on beach
    Second helicopter landing
    Ed Hudson with beer
    Scenes from helicopter
    Second helicopter taking off
    Wreck of first helicopter
    Rescue of passengers by second helicopter
    Second helicopter lands on south rim
    Swimming in Havasu Creek
    Man with horse (Bundys at Whitmore Wash?)
  - Desloge family home movies, undated; VHS videocassette Black and white, silent (Cassette 2.2)
    Probably in Missouri:
    Children on swings
    Playing with dogs
    Climbing trees
    Swimming
    Biking
  - Grand Canyon river trip, circa 1951; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 2.3)
    Flying over Lees Ferry, Navajo Bridge, rapids in Marble Canyon
    Aerial tramway cable spools
    Airplane landing at Marble Canyon airstrip
    Power boats arriving at Lees Ferry on trailers
    Unloading, launching boats
    Putting one boat back on trailer for unknown reason
    Boats in river
    Water-skiing on river
    Looking down on boats from Navajo Bridge
    Boats in rapids: Badger, Soap Creek
    F.M. Brown inscriptions below Soap Creek
    North rim scene
    Repairing propellor on ASweet Chariot" (boat)
    Boats on river
    Swimming in Little Colorado River
    Camp
    River and rapids
    Repairing ASweet Chariot" again
    Boats tied up on bank
    Landing, repairing unnamed blue boat
    People swimming rapids
    Basalt formations below Lava Falls
    Landing "June Bug" (boat)
    Water skiing, lower Grand Canyon
    Views of crews and boats
  - Green River river trip, undated; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 3.1)
    Navajos weaving
    Dust devils from car
    Reynolds River Expeditions boats in rapids: Disaster Falls, Triplet Falls, Hell's Half Mile
    Camp, chopping wood by cabin (where?)
    Loading boats
    Unloading boats
    Hatch River Expeditions pontoons in rapids
    Lining Reynolds River Expeditions boats
    Hatch pontoon stuck on rock
  - Grand Canyon river trip, circa 1951; VHS videocassette Color, silent, out of focus (Cassette 3.2)
    Same trip as 2.3 filmed by a different person:
    Water skiing behind boats
    Men shaving
    Mud
    Boat on river
    Camping
    Boats on river, entrance to Inner Gorge
    Repairing propellors
    VBoats in Hance Rapid
    Mules with supplies
    Riding mules
    Boats in rapids, one broken down and under tow
    Swimming Tapeats Creek
    Granite Falls
  - Green River river trip, undated; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 3.3)
    First scene badly over-exposed
    Men at "Illinois Girl" (wrecked boat) at Winnie's Rapid
    Boats running Disaster Falls
    Camp: cooking, kitchen area, sleeping bags rolled out.
    Scene shifts to Missouri:
    Men drilling water well
    1953 Chevrolet pickup truck
    Family on porch
  - Green River river trip, undated; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 3.4)
    Titles in the film are in quotes:
    "Red Canyon"
    Sheepherder along river
    Camp: cooking
    "Ashley Falls"
    High water runs of Ashley Falls
    "Red Creek Rapids"
    Camp scenes in Hideout Flats?
    "Lodore"
    Triplet Falls
    Boats in fast water
    Buster Basin
    Man swimming rapid
    "Hell's Half Mile"
    Lining boats through Hell's Half Mile
    Camp scenes
    Echo Park
    Passengers and crew: "Joe Desloge, Marie Saalfrank, Hugh Cutler, Marian Cutler, chief boatman A.K. Reynolds, boatmen Lug Larsen, Walt Furen"
    Chipmunks in camp
    Camp at mouth of Split Mountain Canyon
    End of trip
  - Down the Colorado River 365 miles from Lees Ferry to Boulder Dam through the Grand Canyon, circa 1950s; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 3.5)
    Men on boat "Rattlesnake"
    Men on boat "Bootoo"
    Men on boat "Cactus"
    "Badger Creek Rapid"
    Boats in Badger Creek rapid
    "Lee's Ferry to Lake Mead (,) 239 miles with a drop of 1945 feet"
    Boats in rapid (out of focus)
    "A Canyon Evening"
    Camp and riverside scenes
    "Looking over a rapid"
    Scouting rapid from shore
    Rapids filmed from boat
    "Three aluminum boats"
    Boats on river at speed
    Travertine
    "The Little Colorado River"
    "A pair of 15 hp motors"
    Scenes of outboard motors and interiors of boats
    Boat repairs
    Boats in Lava Falls
    "Horn Creek Rapid" (sic - actually looks like Granite Falls)
    Boats in Hermit Rapid
    Damaged boat on shore
    Man with two-way radio
    Looking at rapid from shore
    Elves Chasm
    Boats on riverbank
    Deer Creek Falls
    "Lava Falls"
    Boats running Lava Falls
    "The last 111 miles of the 350 miles were on Lake Mead"
    Boats at speed on Lake Mead
    "Lake Mead and the last camp site"
    Camp on Lake Mead with power launch
    "Silt has filled the head of the lake"
    Scenes on Lake Mead
    Mud cracks
    Bill Belknap?
    Frank Masland
    Joe Desloge
  - Through the Grand Canyon by aluminum boat and outboard motor from Lee's Ferry, Arizona to Boulder City, Nevada on Lake Mead, 1956 June 4-11; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 3.6)
    Possibly the same trip as 3.5
    "Cameras of: Ballard Atherton, Bill Beer, Hugh Cutler, Josh Eisaman, (Otis) Dock Marston, Arch (Frank) Masland"
    Hand tracing route on map
    Marble Canyon trading post
    Navajo Bridge
    "Lee's Ferry June 1"
    Boats on shore
    Working on boats
    Launch
    Otis Marston and ?
    Willy Taylor
    Garth Marston
    Bill Beer
    Unidentified man/ Garth Marston
    "We're Off!"
    Going up river into lower Glen Canyon
    Under Navajo Bridge
    "Badger Creek Rapid from rim"
    Boats in rapid, landing below
    "Soap Creek Rapid"
    Boats in rapid, shot from boat
    "242 Mile Rapid"
    Boats in rapid, shot from shore
    Replacing propellor on one boat
    Motoring through Marble Canyon
    Redwall Cavern (flooded)
    Marble Canyon scenery
    Rapid, men with cameras
    "Pres. (sic) Harding Rapid"
    Boats running rapid
    Stopped for lunch
    Fast water
    "Little Colorado River"
    Boats stopped up Little Colorado River, swimming in blue water
    Camp: making beds, cooking, eating
    "Unkar Rapid"
    View of Unkar delta and rapid from cliffs above
    "Hance Rapid"
    Boats in Hance rapid (several different versions)
    Bill Beer swimming Hance rapid
    Entering Inner Gorge
    Phantom Ranch: eating lunch at table, swimming in pool
    "Granite Falls Rapid"
  - Duplicate of 3.6, VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 4.1)
  - Running Grand Canyon of Colorado River, Desloge-Sanderson Expedition, 1956 September; VHS videocassette Color, silent, out of focus (Cassette 4.2)
    Boats: one S-rig, one double pontoon)
    Phantom Ranch
    Bright Angel Creek
    Views from south rim of Grand Canyon
    Hiking down Kaibab Trail
    Mule train
    Airport at South Rim
    Applying first aid for blistered feet
    Springs on left side below Lava Falls
    Other boats
    Elves Chasm (out of sequence)
    De-rigging boats at Diamond Creek
  - Nevills Expeditions San Juan River river trip, circa 1940s; VHS videocassette Color, silent, backwards (Cassette 4.3)
    Hiking with Norman Nevills
    Cooking, camp scenes
    Pres Walker
    Climbing, hiking
    Boats on river: Gunsight Butte
    Rainbow Bridge
    Mud bathing
    Crossing of the Fathers plaque
    Standing on driftwood log in river
    End of trip at Lees Ferry
    Boats on trailer
    Navajo baby
    Norman Nevills
    The rest of the film is out of sequence:
    Camp, hiking
    Film is no longer backwards:
  - Nevills Expeditions Grand Canyon river trip, circa 1947-1948; VHS videocassette Color, silent, backwards (Cassette 5.1)
    Rattlesnake
    Norman Nevills holding rattlesnake by tail
    Scouting rapids from shore
    Landing boat, hauling on shore
    Cooking, eating
    Rapids: Bedrock Rapid? (wrecked barge on top of middle rock)
    Havasu Creek: swimming, climbing, diving
    Lining Lava Falls
    Building cairn
    Tow out on Lake Mead
  - Reynolds-Hallacy Expeditions Green River river trip, undated; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 5.2)
    Gates of Lodore
    Boat stuck on rock
    Triplet Rapid
    Lining Hell's Half Mile Rapid
  - Nevills Expeditions Green River river trip, circa 1947; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 5.3)
    Ashley Falls high water run
  - Better copy of 4.2 (in focus), VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 5.4)
  - Edited version of 4.3 (not backwards), VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 5.5)
  - Edited version of 5.1, VHS videocassette Black and white, silent (Cassette 5.6)
  - Duplicate of 5.2, VHS videocassette Black and white, silent (Cassette 5.7)
  - Nevills Expeditions Green River river trip, circa 1947; VHS videocassette Color, silent, backwards (Cassette 5.8)
    Longer version of the same trip as 5.3:
    Ashley Falls high water run, more footage than 5.3
    Man in life vest floating through rapid
    Scenery
  - Desloge family home movies, undated; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 5.9)
    Boat or barge trip on Hudson River
    West Point
    New York Harbor
    Brooklyn Bridge
    New York City skyline
    U.S.N. destroyer
    United Nations building
    New York skyline with Chrysler Building
    Amphibious car
    Chinese Junk
    Boys on barge
    Goodyear blimp
    Riding pony, horses
    Family estate?
  - Nevills Expeditions San Juan River trip, circa 1940s; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 5.10-5.12)
    Norman Nevills, Preston Walker, Kent Frost, Joseph Desloge, Joseph Desloge Jr., Marie Saalfrank, Anne Desloge, Zoe Desloge
    Playing in river
    Filming boats
    Petroglyphs
    Hiking, climbing
    Burning driftwood jammed in side canyon
    Wrestling
    Hiking back to boats
    Filling water jugs
    Boating
    Lunch
    Running rapid
    Building cairn with message in can
    Camp on driftwood beach
    Bright Angel creek
    Out of sequence:
    Lower Granite Gorge, Travertine Falls, fluting, rapids
    Deer Creek Falls hike
    Around Lava falls
    Boating, swimming
    Climbing
    Separation Rapid plaque
    Randall Henderson
    Columbine Falls
    Power cruiser, floatplane on Lake Mead
    Signing register books at Rainbow Bridge (?)
    Hiking on slickrock
    Back on boat
    Girl in wild swimsuit
    Lizards
    Shaving
    Mud baths
    Sitting on boats
    Grooming
    Norman Nevills shaving
    Meeting people on shore with dog
    Boat on trailer
  - Nevills Expeditions Green River river trip, circa 1949; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 6.1)
    Ceremony at Expedition Island, Wyoming
    Dedication of Powell monument
    Start of river trip
    Horses swimming in river
    Firehole Towers
    Girl
    Stop at ranch
    Livestock
    Flaming Gorge
    Horseshoe Canyon
    Ashley Falls
    Boating in Red Canyon
    Ashley Falls again (out of sequence, black and white - this segment may have been spliced in)
    Boats in rapid, one person swimming
    Red Creek Rapid
    Breaking camp
    Red Canyon
    Hiking at old ranch
    Riding horses
  - Nevills Expeditions Grand Canyon river trip, circa 1947-1948; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 6.2)
    Much of this footage also appears in 1.2 and 1.3:
    Map of river
    Street scene, San Francisco
    Green River view of canyon from cliffs above
    Aerial of confluence of Colorado and Green Rivers
    Cataract Canyon
    Nevills boat in rapid
    Glen Canyon: Outlaw Cave, mouth of San Juan River